Finding Aid for Marvin Fisher papers, 1972-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Marvin Fisher papers 1972-1976
Fisher, Marvin, 1905-1976.
0.3 linear feet
85150 Aa 2
Chippewa Indian from Bay City, Michigan. Topical files relating to his activities on behalf of Indian rights, including his interest in native American education, land claims, and disputes over hunting and fishing rights.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from Mrs. Vivian Meredith (donor no. 5831 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Marvin Fisher was a Chippewa Indian activist from Bay City, Michigan. He was involved in various organization and causes, including native American education, land claims, and disputes over hunting and fishing rights.
The collection consists of topical files detailing Marvin Fisher's organizational activities and his interest in native American causes in general.
Subjects:
Bay City (Mich.); Ojibwa Indians--Michigan; Education--Michigan.; Indians of North America--Michigan.
- Topical files
  - Saginaw Chippewa Indian tribe of Michigan, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Ottawa Indian land dispute, 1971-1976 (Box 1)
  - Genesee Valley Indian Association by-laws (Box 1)
  - Michigan Commission of Indian Affairs, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Native American education
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Minutes of the Bay County Parent Advisory Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    - Population and school enrollment material, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
    - Saginaw County Indian census, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    - Indian education conference materials, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Regional Advisory Council, Mid-Michigan College Consortium materials, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
    - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Saginaw Valley Career Conference, notes about, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Native American Career Conference, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Bay City Man-Power Planning Council, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Indian Man-Power Advisory Council, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Native American bibliographical miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Multi-ethnic handbook, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Hunting and fishing rights dispute, clippings about, 1971-1974 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Bay City block grant, Public hearing on, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Citizens District Council minutes, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Health Facilities Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Appointment book, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)